# Aliya Robinson

### Front-End Developer

aliya.robinson@gmail.com

# Summary

A self-motivated Software Engineer with over five years of experience in building websites and web applications. Background includes strong knowledge of front-end development with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, External Api's, cross-browser compliance, SEO practices, as well as a good amount of experience with CMS Development in Wordpress and Tumblr. Great communication and troubleshooting skills, well-organized, accomplished, able to work independently on multiple projects, and adapts to dynamic teams and projects.

- -- Recent Experience Managing and Leading Node.js based CMS project for companies video wall. Utilizing Node.js, MonogDB, Express, and Socket.io
- -- Strong background with responsive web development and cross-browser compliance

## Experience

### Freelance Web Developer at Freelance

February 2010 - Present (6 years 10 months)

Working on small website projects for direct clients while also working on personal web projects.

### Marketing Engineer at Chartbeat

June 2015 - March 2016 (10 months)

Developer of interactive marketing projects for Chartbeat.

### Software Engineer (Front-End) at Infor | Hook & Loop

June 2014 - May 2015 (1 year)

- \* Rapid Interactive Prototyping
- \* Build of Infor.com Internal Micro Sites
- \* Build of Infor.com pages
- \* Product Front-End Builds

#### **Associate Front-End Developer at MRY (Formerly Lbi)**

January 2012 - March 2014 (2 years 3 months)

- -Developed interactive web pages using JS/jQuery, HTML, CSS2/3
- -Built HTML email templates
- -Built Facebook tabs
- -Troubleshooted Javascript/jQuery issues on client websites.

### Contract Front-End Developer at Sotheby's International Realty via The Creative Group

October 2011 - December 2011 (3 months)

Worked with Sotheby's International Realty as their Contract Front-End Developer via The Creative Group. I created mock-ups for new pages and build pages with HTML, CSS, and Javascript/jQuery.

### Outsourced Freelance Web & Flash Designer at Hit Web Design

June 2008 - January 2010 (1 year 8 months)

- Coordinate, design, and develop small business websites
  using Dreamweaver, Flash, Photoshop, After Effects, Zen Cart and
  knowledge in HTML/DHTML and PHP.
  - Update changes needed for websites by reading code of other designers and assessing optimal method for updating client's website.
  - -Provided excellent customer service to customers of HIT Web Design.

#### CRM Consultant, IBM Global Business Services at IBM

September 2004 - December 2006 (2 years 4 months)

- Served as liaison between testing and development teams during complex consulting projects including the Onstar General Motors call center system integration project which was the most complex Siebel consulting project taken on to date.
- Cleared up technical fixes needed by working closely with key contacts of the IBM business team and India based consulting firm, Wipro Technologies, application development team.
- Prepared documentation of testing results and research needs for General Motors system upgrade and integration projects.

# Skills & Expertise

**CSS** 

**PHP** 

**HTML** 

Dreamweaver

**Front-end** 

**jQuery** 

Flash

**Web Development** 

Web Design

**User Interface Design** 

**Photoshop** 

**SEO** 

WordPress

MongoDB

# CMS HTML5 JavaScript

## Education

## **Pace University**

Certificate in Adobe Graphic Digital Design, Graphic Design, 2011 - 2011

## **Purchase College, SUNY**

BA, Mathematics/Computer Science, 2003 - 2004

Grade: 3.33

### **Xavier University of Louisiana**

Mathematics, Computer Science, 1994 - 1997

Activities and Societies: SEM Fellow

### **Interests**

Data Visualization, CSS3/HTML5, Samba, Learning Arabic

# Aliya Robinson

Front-End Developer

aliya.robinson@gmail.com



# 2 people have recommended Aliya

"Aliya is a great professional and excellent web designer that gives many options to choose from for every single item of the design. She's also extremely knowledgeable of Wordpress development. She has great patience and working with her is a great pleasure."

— Oksana Tanasiv, Owner, Oksana Tanasiv Art LLC, was Aliya's client

"I am honored to endorse Aliya as a talented front-end developer and team member. Hiring Aliya was one of the best decisions I made as Manager of Software Development while at Hook & Loop. There she focused on the presentation layer of a number of projects, working as a design-driven developer who helped bring ideas to life using her HTML, CSS, JS, and JQuery skills. Her solutions were elegant, unique, and always effective, as she helped many projects move from abstract concepts to functional models. Behind the scenes, her code was always clean, structured, and organized, so she could quickly make changes when needed, or could easily pass it on to a colleague. In addition to her front-end work, Aliya was also a smart and curious programmer, learning new techniques and frameworks quickly to solve more complex, in-depth challenges. Aliya is a great collaborator and communicator, working closely with her dev team members, as well as designers and management, making sure projects consistently met expectations. She's a friendly, engaging and kind person; she will be an asset to any dev team."

— **Ted Kusio**, *Manager of Software Development - Infor | Hook & Loop*, *Infor*, managed Aliya at Infor | Hook & Loop

Contact Aliya on LinkedIn